<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<metadata>
    <name>Lazy Delver</name>
    <directory>lazy_delver</directory>
    <id>3751630929</id>
    <description>
[strike]WORKS ON MY MACHINE[/strike] [url=https://github.com/dokee39/IsaacLazyDelver]GitHub[/url]

Primarily for [b]Repentance[/b]; other versions are untested but may be compatible.
主要适用于[b]忏悔[/b]版本，其他版本未经测试但可能兼容。

[h1]Lazy Delver[/h1]

Marks possible locations for Secret Rooms and Super Secret Rooms on the mini-map, gradually eliminating incorrect candidates as you explore.

[h2]Usage[/h2]
[list]
[*][b]Hold Tab[/b] to show markers
[*]Marker colors:
[list]
[*][b]White[/b] — Normal Secret Room candidate
[*][b]Gold[/b] — Super Secret Room candidate
[*][b]Red[/b] — Ultra Secret Room candidate (only shown while holding Red Key / Cracked Key / Soul of Cain)
[/list]
[*]Marker brightness:
[list]
[*][b]Bright[/b] — All adjacent rooms have been entered and the door‑to‑wall path is passable
[*][b]Dim[/b] — Some adjacent rooms have not yet been explored
[/list]
[*]After entering a room, if a candidate’s door‑to‑wall path is blocked (a solid wall with no door), that candidate is removed
[*]Bomb explodes near a door position → if the corresponding candidate is a fake, its marker is removed
[*]Once the real Secret Room appears on the floor map, all fake candidates of the same type are automatically cleared
[/list]

[h2]Compatible Items &amp; Special Handling[/h2]
[list]
[*]Active items
[list]
[*]Crystal Ball
[*]Book of Secrets
[*]Dad's Key
[/list]
[*]Cards
[list]
[*]XIX - The Sun
[*]XXI - The World
[*]Ansuz
[*]Get Out Of Jail Free Card
[*]Soul of Cain
[/list]
[*]Pills
[list]
[*]I Can See Forever!
[/list]
[*]Passive items
[list]
[*]Blue Map
[*]X-Ray Vision
[*]The Mind
[*]Dog Tooth
[*]YO LISTEN!
[*]Spelunker Hat
[/list]
[*]Compatible with Mirrored World
[*]Curse of the Lost / Home / the Ascent / Greed Mode / special rooms not displayed on the map: not handled
[/list]

[h2]Notes[/h2]
[list]
[*]Because The Binding of Isaac does not provide mini‑map APIs, it is not possible to freely draw on or inspect the mini-map state. Markers can therefore only be shown by manually calculating positions when Tab is pressed.
[*]Normal Secret Rooms typically connect to 2 or more rooms. Only in extremely rare cases does a Normal Secret Room connect to just one room. Therefore, the mod only marks candidate positions with 2 or more connections, while guaranteeing that the real Secret Room is always marked. The same applies to Ultra Secret Rooms.
[*]The candidate markers may not cover every edge case. If you find a reproducible issue, please report it via an issue or in the comments.
[*]Bomb detection range is limited (radius ~80 pixels); an explosion must occur close to the door position for it to trigger exclusion. Using Terra / rock wave or other methods will [b]not[/b] remove candidates.
[/list]

[h1]Lazy Delver[/h1]

在下小地图上标记隐藏房和超级隐藏房的[b]可能位置[/b]，随探索逐步排除错误位置。

[h2]用法[/h2]
[list]
[*][b]按住 Tab 键[/b] 显示标记
[*]标记颜色：
[list]
[*][b]白色[/b] — 普通隐藏房候选
[*][b]金色[/b] — 超级隐藏房候选
[*][b]红色[/b] — 究极隐藏房候选（红钥匙/红钥匙碎片/该隐的魂石持有时才显示）
[/list]
[*]标记亮度：
[list]
[*][b]明亮[/b] — 该位置所有相邻房间均已进入过，门到墙的路径可通行
[*][b]暗淡[/b] — 部分相邻房间尚未探查
[/list]
[*]进入房间后，若某个候选位置的门到墙路径被阻断（墙壁完整无门），该候选被移除
[*]炸弹在门位附近爆炸 → 若对应的是假候选则排除标记
[*]真实隐藏房在楼层地图上出现后，同类假候选自动清除
[/list]

[h2]兼容物品与特殊情况处理[/h2]
[list]
[*]主动道具
[list]
[*]水晶球
[*]秘密之书
[*]爸爸的钥匙
[/list]
[*]卡牌
[list]
[*]XIX-太阳
[*]XXI-世界
[*]诸神符文
[*]免费保释卡
[*]该隐的魂石
[/list]
[*]药丸
[list]
[*]我能永远看清！
[/list]
[*]被动道具
[list]
[*]蓝地图
[*]X光透视
[*]思想
[*]狗牙
[*]嘿，听好！
[*]探窟帽
[/list]
[*]兼容镜像世界
[*]迷途诅咒/家/回溯/贪婪模式/不在地图上的特殊房间：不处理
[/list]

[h2]注意事项[/h2]
[list]
[*]由于以撒没有提供小地图相关的 API，无法自由绘制或检查小地图状态，所以只能在按下 TAB 时手动计算位置显示标记。
[*]标记候选可能无法覆盖所有特殊情况，如果有确定可复现的问题欢迎提 issue 或在评论区反馈。
[*]普通隐藏房一般与大于等于 2 个房间相连接，只有在极少数情况下，普通隐藏房才只与一个房间相连接，因此模组仅标记连接数大于等于二的候选位置，但保证真实隐藏房一定被标记。究极隐藏房也类似。
[*]炸弹检测范围有限（半径约 80 像素），需在门位附近爆炸才能触发排除。使用地球/岩石波等其他手段不会排除候选。
[/list]</description>
    <version>1.0.1</version>
    <visibility>Public</visibility>
    <tag id="Lua"/>
    <tag id="Rooms"/>
</metadata>
